<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Search><pages Count="25"><page Index="1"><![CDATA[THE

ESAKI INFOTAINMENT

        Volume 1, Issue 2

               (INFORMATION & ENTERTAINMENT)

                            CBSE Affiliation No : 1930680
        Tenkasi – Tirunelveli Main Road, Vaikapaalam, Tenkasi – 627811

                         Ph : 04633 – 221991, 8220677119
                 E-Mail : esakividyaashram.cbse.edu@gmail.com
                  Website : http://www.esakividyaashramcbse.in]]></page><page Index="2"><![CDATA[Dr. Esakki Subaya, the Chairman of the school officially brought out the first issue of
E-Magazine Virtually. He also wised all the best to the kith and kin of the school.

         THE

         ESAKI INFOTAINMENT

                BIMONTHLY

               Volume 1, Issue 1

                         (INFORMATION & ENTERTAINMENT)

      ESAKI VIDYAASHRAM, TENKASI

                                      CBSE Affiliation No : 1930680
                 Tenkasi – Tirunelveli Main Road, Vaikapaalam, Tenkasi – 627811

                                   Ph : 04633 – 221991, 8220677119
                           E-Mail : esakividyaashram.cbse.edu@gmail.com
                           Website : http://www.esakividyaashramcbse.in]]></page><page Index="3"><![CDATA[I am happy to say that Esaki Vidyaashram, Tenkasi
                                                   tries to include the digital learning in the
                                                   pedagogy. We inculcate moral values, good
                                                   manners and social responsibilities in students;
                                                   hence they will be in a free zone of evils.
                                                   The temple of education helps the students to
                                                   focus on their subjects that shape their dreams
                                                   and ambitions

  Mr. Esaki Durai
(Managing Director)

           (5th AUG 2022)]]></page><page Index="4"><![CDATA[Message

Greetings from Esaki Vidyaashram !
“Life is about creating us, not finding
us”. The world is full of opportunities,
if we care to look around and spot them.
It means we have to utilize the opportunities
in its apt time.
“What is used less becomes useless”
All are having certain inborn talents in one
way or other.
Don’t hoard the talents; don’t dole it out like
a miser, spend it lavishly. We are judged by
what we offer to the society and our attitude
is the parameter of success.
Wish you all the BEST

Dr. Monica D’Souza

          (Principal)]]></page><page Index="5"><![CDATA[Message

Mr. RAMA KUMAR T; EXECUTIVE DIRECTOR

A construction supervisor from the second floor called a worker who was on the ground
floor. But the worker did not hear his call. The supervisor threw a 10 rupee note in front
of the worker, just to draw his attention. He picked up the note and put it in his pocket
and continued his work.
Then the supervisor threw 500 rupee note but the worker did the same. At last the
supervisor threw a small stone upon the worker. When the stone hit the worker, he
looked up.
Likewise God wants to communicate with us but we are always busy in our work. We
have no time to stand and stare God. Still he gives us some gifts. We receive them
happily, but do not think from where we get it. When we are hit with a small stone we
feel pain and we look up to God. When we are happy we do not remember Him
We have to communicate with God daily before going to bed
Dear students,
“God Fearing” is a good quality in this modern world
Best Wishes]]></page><page Index="6"><![CDATA[Captains and Vice-Captains nominated

28th June: The School nominated House Captains and Vice – Captains to its four houses namely,

      1) Emerald 2 ) Sapphire 3) Ruby 4) Citrine

         Their nomination criteria were the following:
    (1) Positive Leadership Quality
    (2) Well organisational skills
    (3) Good conduct towards the whole school community.
    (4) The role model

The role and responsibilities of the captains:

    (1) Encouraging fellow students to participate in house activities and competitions.
    (2) Sustaining the spirit of the house and bidding fellow students to maintain discipline during house

         activities
         Vice Captains have to assist the House Captains

HOUSE CAPTAINS

M. HARRIS-11C  T. ANISTAN-11B  S.R. AJAY KUMAR-11B J. SURYA-11C

Vice-Captains

HEPZI-11A      K. DHIKSHA-11A  J. SHREYAH-11C  V.MADHUMITHA-11D]]></page><page Index="7"><![CDATA[.]]></page><page Index="8"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="9"><![CDATA[Indian schools opened online teaching strategy when the schools closed due to
Covid-19 pandemic holidays. It was an accidental step. Almost all new steps were
accidentally taken. Then the students, teachers and school managements enjoyed
online teaching system. It was utilized in a fruitful manner. In the advent of it, all had
a freezing doubt whether it might work as fit as a fiddle.

How can we make online teaching a fruitful one?

After school hours, online teaching will be a great help to students for solving their
immediate problems like home assignments and clarifying their doubts. A close
proximity of the teachers with students during 5pm to 7pm will be a relief to both
parents and students. A wise teacher can utilize internet to do the effective teaching
learning process in an interesting way. There should be a wise planning to chalk
down the online classes. It should not be burdensome.

What are the drawbacks of online teaching?

Network problem and non-availability of a handy and sophisticated mobiles, laptops
or computers are some of the notable problems. Watching the system throughout
the day causes physical strain to students. There is ample opportunity to cut the
online classes easily. Sitting in a room and conducting online classes even without a
black board seems to be awkward. The teacher should be updated with the online
teaching.

In short, if school managements, teachers and parents work together with maximum
co-operation and solidarity, online teaching after school hours will yield pink result
and it will pave the way to innovative teaching learning process within a short span.
Long live India’s cultural heritage and teaching learning process.]]></page><page Index="10"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="11"><![CDATA[By Sakthi Narayan, Grade 12 B3 (1)

According to a recent survey undertaken by a group of scientists reveals that
a banana a day will keep away the depression. This is because bananas
contain tryptophan, a kind of protein that the body converts into serotonin,
known to make you relax, improve your mood and generally make you feel
happier.

It has vitamin B6, which regulates blood glucose level, which can affect your
mood. The banana has high iron content, which will stimulate the
production of haemoglobin in the blood and so helps in cases of anaemia

One of the quickest ways of curing a hangover is to make a banana
milkshake, sweetened with honey. This unique tropical fruit is extremely
high in potassium yet low in salt, making it perfect to beat the blood
pressure.]]></page><page Index="12"><![CDATA[The sun peeped down from the eastern sky in the same place without any delay. There danced a light breeze.
The branches of the trees nodded left and right welcoming the day break.

The crows flapped their wings and flew high. They cried „craw, craw, and craw‟.

Muthu Chami, the farmer woke up and tended his buffalos and cows. He gave them alfalfa and oats.

His wife milked the cows. Its calf ran up and down. Along with the wind, there spread the smell of mud and cow dung.

“It‟s already late, take the milk to the tea shop”, she said to him showing an aluminium canister. He nodded and said
nothing. He was brushing his teeth with a thin stick of a neem tree. His wife looked at him when he rode the bicycle
hanging the canister in its handle.

It was not morning yet. The road was wet and slippery. There was water in its pits. Suddenly the front wheel of the
cycle ran into a large pit. He lost his control and fell down. A huge tripper lorry came fast from behind and ran over
him.

The muddy water soaked him. The tripper didn‟t stop. Many people crowded there. Muthu Chami was hospitalised. The
next day, the village witnessed a funeral procession with wet eyes.]]></page><page Index="13"><![CDATA[A class on solid waste management was held on 4th July ’22 by Mr.
Eswaran, Sanitary Inspector of Tenkasi Municipality. He was assisted by
Mr. Madhavan Rajkumar and Mr. Sekar.

Improper disposal of municipal solid waste can create unsanitary
conditions, and these conditions in turn can lead to pollution of the
environment and to outbreaks of vector borne disease – that is diseases
spread by rodents and insects.

Solid waste includes garbage and rubbish. Garbage is mostly
decomposable whereas rubbish is mostly not. Trash is rubbish that
includes e-waste. Waste management deals with all types of wastes,
including industrial, biological, household municipal, radioactive etc.

The waste management aims to reduce the dangerous effects on the
environment and human health

 Reduce, Reuse and Recycle are the present day slogan.

        Recycle

Reduce

        Reuse]]></page><page Index="14"><![CDATA[KINDERGARTEN

At pre-primary level we work hard to ensure our children enjoy learning. It is
said that children learn well when they are interested, creatively engaged. Only
through love we can motivate them to be a lover of books and alphabet.
We give them guidance to increase their self-esteem and love the books.
The students should be happy and confident with self-belief, positive thinkers,
good communicators and listeners. If they achieve all these, the students will be
confident to face any challenges.

   ]]></page><page Index="15"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="16"><![CDATA[BALLOONS DAY CELEBRATED]]></page><page Index="17"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="18"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="19"><![CDATA[In India, The Teachers’ Day is celebrated on 5th Sept and this tradition started from 1962. It is the
birthday of Dr. Sarvepalli Radhakrishnan, who was a philosopher, Scholar, Teacher and Politician. His
dedicated work towards education made his birthday “The Teachers’ day” , an important day in the
history of India.]]></page><page Index="20"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="21"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="22"><![CDATA[A study tour is an experience where students study as an alternative to traditional class
room based learning. Students of Grade I and II visited Tenkasi Railway Station on 15the
Sept 2022. They learnt how to take platform ticket, booking berths, where passengers have
to wait etc. Students and teachers who accompanied them remarked in single voice that it

was a grand SUCCESS]]></page><page Index="23"><![CDATA[“NOT MATTER HOW YOU FEEL,
           GET
         DRESS
         SHOW

& NEVER GIVE “]]></page><page Index="24"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="25"><![CDATA[EDITORIAL

This humble initiative is to set the budding minds free allowing them
to roam free to create a world of beauty in words

This e- magazine espouses the schooling spirit which is built up with
in the school through the collective actions, thoughts and aspirations

Wish you best of luck

                            CHANDRAN. M. K
                            Editor – in – Chief

Editorial Board Members:    1.Mrs.Kamala Nachiyar
Web Layout and Designing :  2. Ms.Shenbaga Pandeeswari
                            3. Mrs.Uma Maheswari
                            4. Mrs.Jamimah
                            5. Mrs.Nancy
                            6. Mrs.Suganya

                            1. Mr. H. Mohammed Abdullah
                            2. Mrs.C.Usha

“ The Backbone of the E-Magazine”]]></page></pages></Search>